A Guide to the Ronald E. Carrier Collection, 1965-1998
Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University
- Speeches1966-1996, (3 Boxes)
  - “Remarks of Dr. Ronald E Carrier, President James Madison University” to the State Council of Higher Education for Virginia” September 4 1985 (Box-folder 4:7)
  - “Parents Day Address” October 26 1985 (Box-folder 4:7)
  - “Address by Dr. Ronald E Carrier President, James Madison University” to Alpha Epsilon Rho East Central Regional Convention November 7 1985 (Box-folder 4:7)
  - “Tribute to a Hog” December 20 1985 (Box-folder 4:7)
  - “Remarks of Dr. Ronald E Carrier President, Shenandoah Valley Education Television Corporation President, James Madison University” The topic is Pat Moss, February 19 1986 (Box-folder 4:7)
  - “Address by Dr. Ronald E Carrier President, James Madison University” to the Naturalization Hearing at the United States District Court—Western District of Virginia” February 21 1986 (Box-folder 4:8)
  - “Remarks of Dr. Ronald E Carrier President, Center for Innovative Technology President, James Madison University” to Multiple Sclerosis Society Benefit Banquet November 10 1986 (Box-folder 4:8)
  - “Address by Russel G. Warren Acting President James Madison University” to the Conference on “Into the Future” for the Virginia Association of Collegiate Registrars and Admissions Officers December 8 1986 (Box-folder 4:8)
  - “Remarks to the Graduates” Address by Dr. Russell G. Warren Acting President James Madison University December 19 1986 (Box-folder 4:8)
  - “The State of the University” 1987 (Box-folder 4:9)
  - “Report on the Economy” 1987 (Box-folder 4:9)
  - “Remarks to the Board of Associates Randolph-Macon College” March 20 1987 (Box-folder 4:9)
  - “Remarks to the Faculty Dr. Ronald E. Carrier President, James Madison University” April 1 1987 (Box-folder 4:9)
  - “Comments Dr. Ronald E. Carrier President James Madison University SGA Picnic” April 27 1987 (Box-folder 4:9)
  - “Remarks to the Graduates” to Stonewall Jackson Senior High School Graduation Exercises June 17 1987 (Box-folder 4:9)
  - “Remarks to the Graduates J. Sargeant Reynolds Community College” June 19 1987 (Box-folder 4:10)
  - “Remarks to the Faculty: General Faculty Meeting” August 28 1987 (Box-folder 4:10)
  - “Remarks of Dr. Ronald E. Carrier President, James Madison University” to Virginia Peninsula Economic Development Council September 14 1987 (Box-folder 4:10)
  - “Welcoming Remarks Dr. Ronald E. Carrier President, James Madison University Montpelier Program on Bicentennial of U.S. Constitution” September 17 1987 (Box-folder 4:11)
  - “Remarks for Dr. Ronald E. Carrier President, James Madison University Virginia Manufacturers Association Hot Springs, Virginia” September 26 1987 (Box-folder 4:11)
  - “State of the University: Remarks to the Students’ Parents” October 10 1987 (Box-folder 4:11)
  - “State of the University” November 11 1987 (Box-folder 4:11)
  - “Dedication Remarks for Roop House” November 14 1987 (Box-folder 4:12)
  - “The State of the University, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 4:12)
  - “Remarks of Dr. Ronald E. Carrier President, James Madison University 16th Annual Service Awards Program” January 13 1988 (Box-folder 4:12)
  - “Speak Out” January 18 1988 (Box-folder 4:12)
  - “Remarks of Dr. Ronald E. Carrier President, James Madison University Parents Council/Alumni Board Meeting” April 9 1988 (Box-folder 4:12)
  - “Comments of Dr. Ronald E Carrier President, James Madison University ROTC Commissioning Ceremony” May 7 1988 (Box-folder 4:13)
  - “Address of Dr. Ronald E Carrier President, James Madison University” to Virginia Hall of Fame Banquet, Junior Achievement of Richmond May 10 1988 (Box-folder 4:13)
  - “Address of Dr. Ronald E Carrier President, James Madison University: Waynesboro –East Augusta Chapter of Commerce” May 26 1988 (Box-folder 4:13)
  - “Remarks of Dr. Ronald E Carrier President, James Madison University, Summer Conference, Virginia PTAs, Longwood College” July 22 1988 (Box-folder 4:14)
  - “Remarks for Dr. Ronald E. Carrier” for the Memorial Service for Dr. G. Tyler Miller July 29 1988 (Box-folder 4:14)
  - “Comments of Dr. Ronald E Carrier President, James Madison University New Faculty Meeting” August 24 1988 (Box-folder 4:14)
  - “Remarks to the Faculty Dr. Ronald E Carrier President, James Madison University” August 26 1988 (Box-folder 4:14)
  - “Remarks by Dr. Ronald E Carrier President, James Madison University Global Education Conference Phillips Center Ballroom” September 27 1988 (Box-folder 4:14)
  - “Remarks of Dr. Ronald E Carrier President, James Madison University Black Students Honors Reception” September 27 1988 (Box-folder 4:14)
  - “Remarks of Dr. Ronald E Carrier President, James Madison University Interfraternity Council” September 27 1988 (Box-folder 4:14)
  - “Welcoming Remarks Dr. Ronald E Carrier President, James Madison University Black Awareness Day” October 1 1988 (Box-folder 4:15)
  - “Parents Day Address” October 22 1988 (Box-folder 4:15)
  - “Acknowledgment” to the Virginia Business Council November 10 1988 (Box-folder 4:15)
  - “The University of the 21st Century” to the Spring Meeting of the American Association of Colleges of Nursing March 27 1990 (Box-folder 5:1)
  - “Address of Dr. Ronald E. Carrier Inauguration of Major General John W. Knapp Virginia Military Institute” March 29 1990 (Box-folder 5:1)
  - “Address of Dr. Ronald E. Carrier Inauguration of Major General John W. Knapp Virginia Military Institute” March 29 1990 (Box-folder 5:1)
  - “Remarks to the Graduating Class” to Bath County High School June 12 1990 (Box-folder 5:1)
  - “Remarks Address of Dr. Ronald E. Carrier President, James Madison University 64th Annual Banquet Page County Chamber of Commerce” June 13 1990 (Box-folder 5:2)
  - “Remarks Address of Dr. Ronald E. Carrier President, James Madison University 64th Annual Banquet Page County Chamber of Commerce” June 13 1990 (Box-folder 5:2)
  - “Welcoming Comments” for the Welcome Reception—Faculty and Staff of Color September 12 1990 (Box-folder 5:2)
  - No title- Speech at Presidents Ball September 15 1990 (Box-folder 5:2)
  - “Welcoming Remarks: College News Association Workshop” October 23 1990 (Box-folder 5:3)
  - “Notes for an Address by Dr. Ronald E. Carrier President, James Madison University” in Norfolk Virginia to mathematicians November 2 1990 (Box-folder 5:3)
  - “Comments of Dr. Ronald E. Carrier President, James Madison University Multiple Sclerosis Dinner of Champions” November 8 1990 (Box-folder 5:3)
  - “Comments of Dr. Ronald E. Carrier President, James Madison University Multiple Sclerosis Dinner of Champions” November 8 1990 (Box-folder 5:3)
  - “Welcoming Comments Dr. Ronald E. Carrier President, James Madison University Conference for Gifted Students” November 9 1990 (Box-folder 5:3)
  - “Dedication Remarks—Bridgeforth Stadium” Pre-game Ceremony November 10 1990 (Box-folder 5:4)
  - “Commencement Address” December 14 1990 (Box-folder 5:4)
  - “Remarks of Dr. Ronald E. Carrier President, James Madison University 19th Annual Service Awards Program, JMU” January 4 1991 (Box-folder 5:4)
  - “Remarks of Dr. Ronald E. Carrier President, James Madison University Candle- Lighting Ceremony 1991 Martin Luther King Jr. Celebration” January 21 1991 (Box-folder 5:4)
  - “JMU’s College of Applied Science and Technology Comments to State Council of Higher Education for Virginia” (Box-folder 5:4)
  - “Notes for Dr. Ronald E. Carrier Remarks for the Arts Group Oakview” February 13 1991 (Box-folder 5:4)
  - “Note for comments to Virginia Alliance for Public Service” March 12 1991 (Box-folder 5:4)
  - “Comments of Dr. Ronald E. Carrier President, James Madison University Fifth Annual JMU Art Auction The Homestead” April 6 1991 (Box-folder 5:5)
  - “Remarks of Dr. Ronald E. Carrier President, James Madison University” to Honors Banquet Annandale Rotary Club April 17 1991 (Box-folder 5:5)
  - “Address to Student Government Association” April 23 1991 (Box-folder 5:5)
  - “Address to Student Government Association” April 23 1991 (Box-folder 5:5)
  - “Address of Dr. Ronald E. Carrier President, James Madison University Inauguration of Dr. Russell G. Warren” April 27 1991 (Box-folder 5:5)
  - “Remarks to the Graduates” May 4 1991 (Box-folder 5:5)
  - “What’s Right With Higher Education” to the Commencement of Virginia Highlands Community College May 14 1991 (Box-folder 5:5)
  - “Remarks of Dr. Ronald E. Carrier President, James Madison University Graduation Ceremony Langley High School” June 13 1991 (Box-folder 5:6)
  - “Remarks of Dr. Ronald E. Carrier President, James Madison University Vespers Service Happy Birthday U.S.A., Celebration” July 3 1991 (Box-folder 5:6)
  - “Remarks to the Graduates Dr. Ronald E. Carrier President, James Madison University August Commencement, 1991” August 2 1991 (Box-folder 5:6)
  - “Comments of Dr. Ronald E. Carrier President, James Madison University Fall Freshmen Convocation, JMU” August 24 1991 (Box-folder 5:6)
  - Speech to the Nelson County Chamber of Commerce October 15 1991 (Box-folder 5:6)
  - “Talking Points Dr. Ronald E. Carrier Science & Technology Awareness Day Latimer/Shaeffer Theatre” October 19 1991 (Box-folder 5:7)
  - “The Business College’s Relevence to the University’s Mission” to the Southern Business Administration Association’s Thirty-Ninth Annual Meeting” November 11 1991 (Box-folder 5:7)
  - “State of the University Address” to the Greater Madison, INC. Annual Banquet November 21 1991 (Box-folder 5:7)
  - “Remarks of Dr. Ronald E. Carrier President, James Madison University Christmas Tree Lighting Ceremony” December 4 1991 (Box-folder 5:7)
  - “Effective Presidential Renewal” given to SAC’s Annual Meeting December 6 1991 (Box-folder 5:8)
  - “Talking Points for Dr. Ronald E. Carrier’s Welcome to the Valley of Virginia Partnership for Education” January 30 1992 (Box-folder 5:8)
  - “Comments of Dr. Ronald E. Carrier President, James Madison University” to the Education Night, Central Virginia Chapter, Financial Executives Institute March 17 1992 (Box-folder 5:8)
  - “Notes Concerning William R. Nelson, Professor of Political Science and Law James Madison University” April 17 1992 (Box-folder 5:8)
  - “Dr. Carrier’s Speech Tech High” 1992 (Box-folder 5:8)
  - Fall Orientation Speech 1992 (Box-folder 5:9)
  - “The Shenandoah Valley--Past Present, and Future” to the House of Delegates Appropriations Committee October 18 1992 (Box-folder 5:9)
  - “Remarks to the Faculty Senate Dr. Ronald E. Carrier President, James Madison University” October 22 1992 (Box-folder 5:9)
  - “Comments of Dr. Ronald E. Carrier President, James Madison University JMU Economic Impact Study Press Conference” December 2 1992 (Box-folder 5:9)
  - “Welcoming Remarks” to AASCU Teach American Conference December 11 1992 (Box-folder 5:9)
  - “Remarks of Dr. Ronald E. Carrier President, James Madison University Speak-Out Program 1993 Martin Luther King, Jr. Celebration” January 18 1993 (Box-folder 5:9)
  - “Notes for Comments to City Council” January 26 1993 (Box-folder 5:10)
  - “Remarks of Dr. Ronald E. Carrier President, James Madison University General Faculty Meeting” August 27 1993 (Box-folder 5:10)
  - “Summary Freshman Convocation” August 28 1993 (Box-folder 5:10)
  - “What’s Right with Higher Education” to Christopher Newport University Founder’s Day September 15 1993 (Box-folder 5:10)
  - “Comments of Dr. Ronald E. Carrier President, James Madison University JMU Faculty Senate Meeting” October 14 1993 (Box-folder 5:10)
  - “Notes for Interview with Breeze on Faculty Senate Address” October 17 1993 (Box-folder 5:10)
  - “Notes/Comments for Second Annual Western Virginia Strategic Development Conference” October 21 1993 (Box-folder 5:11)
  - Speech to the Distinguished Citizen Awards Dinner for the Boy Scouts December 2 1993 (Box-folder 5:11)
  - “Remarks to the Faculty” December 7 1993 (Box-folder 5:11)
  - “Comments of Dr. Ronald E. Carrier President, James Madison University, University Council” January 13 1994 (Box-folder 5:11)
  - “Remarks of Dr. Ronald E. Carrier President, James Madison University, Spring Faculty Meeting” April 27 1994 (Box-folder 5:11)
  - “Comments of Dr. Ronald E. Carrier President, James Madison University, Hearing of Education Subcommittee, Senate Finance Committee” July 11 1994 (Box-folder 5:12)
  - “Comments of Dr. Ronald E. Carrier President, James Madison University, New Faculty Orientation” August 24 1994 (Box-folder 5:12)
  - “Comments of Dr. Ronald E. Carrier President, James Madison University, Opening Faculty Meeting—1994-95 Session” August 26 1994 (Box-folder 5:12)
  - “Comments of Dr. Ronald E. Carrier President, James Madison University, Senate Finance Committee/ House Appropriations Committee Joint Hearing” September 28 1994 (Box-folder 5:12)
  - “Welcoming Comments Dr. Ronald E. Carrier President, James Madison University, Furious Flower Conference” September 29 1994 (Box-folder 5:12)
  - “Comments of Dr. Ronald E. Carrier President, James Madison University, Parents Meeting -- Parents Weekend” October 15 1994 (Box-folder 5:12)
  - “Comments of Dr. Ronald E. Carrier President, James Madison University, 24th Annual Service Awards Program, James Madison University” January 15 1995 (Box-folder 5:13)
  - “Comments of Dr. Ronald E. Carrier President, James Madison University, Roop Hall Dedication” April 21 1995 (Box-folder 5:13)
  - “Presentation to Regional Economic Development Meeting” November 9 1995 (Box-folder 5:13)
  - “Remarks to the Graduates, December Commencement” December 15 1995 (Box-folder 5:13)
  - “Welcoming Comments Dr. Ronald E. Carrier President, James Madison University, Land Use and Conservation Forum” April 13 1996 (Box-folder 5:13)
  - “Matt Montgomery Memorial Service” September 4 1996 (Box-folder 5:13)
  - “Remarks for JMU Faculty Women’s Caucus” September 5 1996 (Box-folder 5:13)
  - “Notes for Welcome Dr. Ronald E. Carrier President, James Madison University, 20th Annual Economic Outlook Seminar” October 16 1996 (Box-folder 5:13)
- Miscellaneous/Undated Speeches, Administrative, and Academic Papers, (1 Boxes)
  - “Americanism” (Box-folder 6:1)
  - “Changing Times”/ “Madison….As it was, as it is, as it will be” (Box-folder 6:1)
  - “Higher Education in 1970” (Box-folder 6:1)
  - “James Madison University: Progress in Academics: The Past” (Box-folder 6:1)
  - “Leaders and Managers” (Box-folder 6:1)
  - “Management in Higher Education” (Box-folder 6:1)
  - “Success in Management” (Box-folder 6:1)
  - “The Social Sciences in the 70’s: Preparation for the 21st Century” (Box-folder 6:1)
  - “The Social Sciences in the 70’s: Preparation for the 21st Century” (Box-folder 6:1)
  - “The Tyranny of ‘Relevance’” (Box-folder 6:1)
  - “What’s Right with Higher Education” (Box-folder 6:1)
  - No Title- Technology and Industry (Box-folder 6:1)
  - No title- Topic is about JMU and the statistics of development and the student population (Box-folder 6:1)
  - No-Title- Given by Colonel Frederick F. Riley on “Six Volcanoes” (Conflicts in the US) (Box-folder 6:1)
  - “Desiderata”1962, Found in Old Saint Paul’s Church, Baltimore (Box-folder 6:2)
  - “Desiderata”- note: Found in Old Saint Paul’s Church, Baltimore, dates 1692 (Box-folder 6:2)
  - “High Technology and Management” June 29th, 1990 (Box-folder 6:2)
  - “Major National Planning Assumptions” (Box-folder 6:2)
  - “The Christian and His World” (Box-folder 6:2)
  - “The Leader Organization: Strategic Vision 1988-1998” (Box-folder 6:2)
  - “The Leader Organization: Strategic Vision: 1998” (Box-folder 6:2)
  - “What to be thankful for” by Louis Bromfield (Box-folder 6:2)
  - No title- agriculture (Box-folder 6:2)
  - No title- appears to be start of Speech for “The Social Sciences in the 70’s” (Box-folder 6:2)
  - No title- Religious/ Annunciation (Box-folder 6:2)
  - “Chronology of James Madison University Arboretum” (Box-folder 6:3)
  - “History of the Arboretum” (Box-folder 6:3)
  - “Program and Concept Outline For The Edith J. Carrier Arboretum James Madison University” February 27 2001 (Box-folder 6:3)
  - “Chapter VI: The Inflationary Impact of Unionism (1945-1958)” (Box-folder 6:4)
  - “Arabs and Jews: Background” (Box-folder 6:4)
  - “Arabs and Jews: Two Points of View” (Box-folder 6:5)
  - “Arabs and Jews: Role of the Superpowers” (Box-folder 6:5)
  - “What is the Middle East?” (Box-folder 6:5)
  - “Highlights of the 1964 Conference on Mississippi’s Economic Growth and Prospects” January 3 1964 (Box-folder 6:)
  - “Witness and Give”- Church Bulletin Sunday October 9 1966 (Box-folder 6:)
  - “Chapter 1 In Action: Virginia Evaluation Summary, 1979-83” July 1984 (Box-folder 6:)
  - “1985 Virginia Chapter 1 Coordinators’ Conference” March 20 1985 (Box-folder 6:)
  - “Ray V. Sonner Ground Breaking” November 5 1988 (Box-folder 6:)
  - “Night of the Hunter” September 18th, 1989 (Box-folder 6:)
  - “Smooth Sailing!: 1989 National Auditing and Legal Affairs Conference” October 17 1989 (Box-folder 6:)
  - “James Madison”- includes article “After more than two centuries, this may be Mr. Madison’s year” (Box-folder 6:7)
  - “Pence Pride Week” (Box-folder 6:7)
  - “The Facts of Life for Affluent Kids” (Box-folder 6:7)
  - “Threat of ‘Managerial Revolution’ Cited by Ohio State Head” (Box-folder 6:7)